Finding Aid for Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives videocassettes, 1986-1989 and undated
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives videocassettes 1986-1989, undated
Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives.
7 linear feet
2011177 Bj 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The videotapes came to the library from the Inter-Cooperative Council (donor no. 3815 ) in May 2011.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives, which was established in 1980, is an association of Michigan food co-ops, farm co-ops, electric co-ops, housing co-ops, credit unions, buying clubs, and other types of co-ops. The function of the Alliance is to support new co-op groups starting up and to meet and consult with these and other co-ops to discuss their common problems.
The Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives videotapes include recordings of programs, oral history interviews, and panel discussions on topics of concern to cooperatives. Most of the tapes are professional broadcast U-matic videocassettes and master broadcast U-matic videocassettes with a few VHS cassettes. Cooperative leaders represented on the tapes include Fred Thornthwaite, Cecil Robert Crews, Luther Buchele, Jack McClanahan, and Joseph L. Hansknecht among others.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives.; Buchele, Luther H., 1920-; Crews, Cecil Robert.; Hansknecht, Joseph L, 1923-; McClanahan, Jack.; Thornthwaite, Fred.; Cooperatives--Michigan.
Genre Terms:
Oral histories.; Videotapes.
- Videotapes, U-matic, professional broadcast videocassettes except where indicated
  - Panel #1 (Box 1)
    (Tape 1)
  - Panel #2 (Box 1)
    (Tape 2)
  - Panel #3 (Box 1)
    (Tape 3)
  - Panel #4 (Box 1)
    (Tape 4)
  - Panel #5 (Box 1)
    (Tape 5)
  - Panel #6 / Interview Cecil Crews (Box 1)
    (Tape 6)
  - Cecil Crews #2 (Box 1)
    (Tape 7)
  - Cecil Crews #3 (Box 1)
    (Tape 8)
  - Cecil Crews #4 (Box 1)
    (Tape 9)
  - Cecil Crews #5 / Fred Thornthwaide #1 (Box 1)
    (Tape 10)
  - Fred Thornthwaide #2 (Box 1)
    (Tape 11)
  - Fred Thornthwaide #3 / Chet Reimbough #1 (Box 1)
    (Tape 12)
  - Chet Reimbough #2 (Box 2)
    (Tape 13)
  - Banquet #2 (Box 2)
    (Tape 14)
  - Banquet #15 / Pioneers #3 (Box 2)
    (Tape 15)
  - Fred and Ving Accepting Award (Box 2)
    (Tape 16)
  - Jack McClanahan #1 (Box 2)
    (Tape 17)
  - Jack McClanahan #2 (Box 2)
    (Tape 18)
  - Jack McClanahan #3 (Box 2)
    (Tape 19)
  - Jack McClanahan #4 (Box 2)
    (Tape 20)
  - Bill Dueweke #1 (Box 2)
    (Tape 21)
  - Bill Dueweke #2 / Jack McClanahan Speech / Luther Buchele #1 (Box 2)
    (Tape 22)
  - Luther Buchele #2 (Box 2)
    (Tape 23)
  - Luther Buchele #3 (Box 2)
    (Tape 24)
  - Luther Buchele #4 (Box 3)
    (Tape 25)
  - Elton Smith #1 (Box 3)
    (Tape 26)
  - Elton Smith #2 (Box 3)
    (Tape 27)
  - Elton Smith #3 (Box 3)
    (Tape 28)
  - Paris Henke / Jim Clark #1 (Box 3)
    (Tape 29)
  - Jim Clark #2 / Doris Henke #1 (Box 3)
    (Tape 30)
  - Willard Henke #1 (Box 3)
    (Tape 31)
  - Willard Henke #2 (Box 3)
    (Tape 32)
  - Willard Henke #3 / Francis Lesnieski #1 (Box 3)
    (Tape 33)
  - Francis Lesnieski #2 (Box 3)
    (Tape 34)
  - Francis Lesnieski #3 (Box 3)
    (Tape 35)
  - Francis Lesnieski #4 (Box 3)
    (Tape 36)
  - Glenn Lake #1 (Box 4)
    (Tape 37)
  - Glenn Lake #2 (Box 4)
    (Tape 38)
  - Glenn Lake #3/Julia Szabo #1 (Box 4)
    (Tape 39)
  - Julia Szabo #2 (Box 4)
    (Tape 40)
  - Julia Szabo #3/Esther Shapiro #1 (Box 4)
    (Tape 41)
  - Esther Shapiro #2 (Box 4)
    (Tape 42)
  - Lee Feller #1 (Box 4)
    (Tape 43)
  - Lee Feller #2 (Box 4)
    (Tape 44)
  - Jack Shelton #1 (Box 4)
    (Tape 45)
  - Jack Shelton #2 (Box 4)
    (Tape 46)
  - Jack Shelton #3 (Box 4)
    (Tape 47)
  - Al Rightley #1 (Box 5)
    (Tape 48)
  - Al Rightley #2 / Jo Hansknecht #1 (Box 5)
    (Tape 49)
  - Jo Hansknecht #2 (Box 5)
    (Tape 50)
  - Jo Hansknecht #3 (Box 5)
    (Tape 51)
  - Jo Hansknecht #4 (Box 5)
    (Tape 52)
  - Random Tape: Banquet #1 (Kids Dancing) (Box 5)
  - Copies of Selected Interviews, VHS cassettes
    - Co-op Conference Panel #1-4, Cecil Crews #6-9, Fred Thornthwaide #10-11, Chet Reimbough #12-13, Banquet #14-16 (Box 5)
    - Jack McClanahan #17-20, Bill Dueweke #21-22, Luther Buchele #23-25 (Box 5)
    - Interviews-Lansing Chapter: Elton Smith #26-28, Jim Clark #29-30, Doris and Willard Henke #29-30 and #31-32, Francis Lesnieski #33-36 (Box 5)
  - Interviews, VHS cassettes
    - Tapes 37-43 July 11, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Tapes 43-48 July 11, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Tapes 49-50 July 11, 1988 (Box 6)
  - "Cooperative Voices" program, VHS cassettes
    - "Cooperative Voices: Speak About Food Co-ops" Parts 1 & 2 -- Rough Cut October 1988, 26:22 (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Script 1-5, Panel: Various Co-op Sectors (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Script 5-11, Panel Cont'd: Various Co-op Sectors, Co-op Governance, Structure, Education, Dairy Co-op, Senior Housing (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Script 11-17, Agriculture Co-ops, Education, Banquet, Pioneer Awards, Co-op Songs, Great Depression, Food Co-ops, Union Support (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Script 18-23, Student Co-ops, NASCO, Influence Society, Agriculture Co-ops, Legislation Int'l Society, Processing Co-ops, Financing (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Script 29-35, Agriculture Co-ops, Electric Co-op, Women, Rural Co-ops, Songs, Credit Unions (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Script 35-41, Credit Union, Milk Co-op, Legislation, Electricity, Senior Housing, Consumer Advocacy, Consumer Advocacy, NAACP (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Script 41-47, Financing, Community, Food Co-op, Administrative Training, Rochdale Principle, Food Co-ops in Europe, Workers Collective-Foraging (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Script 48-52, Labor Movement, Food Co-ops, Credit Unions, Alternative to Capitalism (Box 6)
    - Cooperative Voices: Speak About Food Co-ops, Part I Edited Master, 8:09; U-matic (Box 6)
    - Cooperative Voices-Sample Preview
      - New Edited Master April 1988, U-matic (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices" (Combined Version), 28:15; U-matic (Box 6)
    - Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives "Cooperative Voices" Part One (9:18); Part Two (11:27); Part Three (10:49), U-matic (Box 6)
    - "Cooperative Voices: Speak About Food Co-ops" Parts I & II October 1988, 26:22; U-matic (Box 6)
    - Michigan Alliance of Cooperatives "Cooperative Voices" April 5, 1989, 31:34; U-matic (Box 6)
    - Introduction for "Cooperative Voices" First DVE pas, U-matic cassette (Box 7)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Master preview, U-matic cassette (Box 7)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Stills March 28, 1989, 2 videotapes U-matic (Box 7)
    - Part II: Cooperative Voices: Speak to Foot Coops October 1988, U-matic cassette (Box 7)
    - "Cooperative Voices" stills, VHS cassette (Box 7)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Sample/Draft preview April 1988, VHS cassette (Box 7)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Preview tape May 1988, VHS cassette (Box 7)
    - "Cooperative Voices" Speak about food coops, Parts I and II October 1988, VHS cassette (Box 7)
  - Master raw footage of "A Tribute to Elton Smith" and 1986 Michigan Farm Bureau Annual Meeting, VHS cassette (Box 7)
  - Interview and Transition Examples, VHS cassette (Box 7)